for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
Kakashi: Shadow of the Anbu
The Targeted Sharingan
The Sharingan is a disposable power.
（ダンゾウ）写輪眼というものは
そもそも　使い捨ての力だ。
Even the Uchiha Clan
who possess the Sharingan...
（ダンゾウ）写輪眼を持つ
うちは一族の者たちですら→
The more they use that power,
the greater the loss of their eyesight...
力を使えば使うほど
その瞳力を失い→
やがて　光すら失うという。
until they finally go blind.
ましてや　写輪眼そのものを
失うことによって発動する→
Furthermore, there is even
a Forbidden Jutsu
that is invoked at the cost
of losing the Sharingan.
禁術まであるのだからな。
わしの　この眼の代わりを
手に入れてこい。
Get me a replacement for
this right eye of mine.
If we are to attack
a member of the Uchiha,
うちはの者を襲うのであれば
周到な準備が必要かと。
careful preparation is necessary.
There is one
who is not an Uchiha...
うちはの者にあらず　親も師もなく
友を殺した者が→
who has neither parents nor teachers,
who has killed his own comrade...
写輪眼を一つ持っている。
Kakashi... Hatake.
（甲）はたけカカシ。
後腐れはない。
Then we won't need to worry
about any future trouble.
RIN NOHARA
Whose grave is it?
誰の墓？
The friend he killed.
アイツが殺した自分の仲間だ。
Kakashi Senpai...
（夕顔）カカシ先輩。
Lord Hokage is calling.
（夕顔）火影様がお呼びです。
（カカシ）わかった。
All right.
Stop calling me "Senpai."
This isn't the academy.
いい加減　先輩はよせ
アカデミーじゃないんだぞ。
You're still my senior in the ANBU.
暗部でも先輩じゃありませんか。
Besides, you're my role model.
私　先輩をお手本にしています。
Find someone more suitable.
もっとマシなヤツを手本にしろ。
おい。
Hey...
のはらリン。
Rin Nohara...
RIN NOHARA
You are aware that Orochimaru
has secret research facilities
大蛇丸が　国のあちこちに
秘密の研究施設を→
scattered throughout the country,
aren't you?
持っていたことは知っておるな。
はい。
Yes.
After he deserted the village,
里抜けの際　大蛇丸は
そのいくつかを破壊し→
he destroyed some and
kept some intact.
いくつかを
そのままに残していきおった。
Including ones that
we have no knowledge of.
わしらの知らぬものも含めてな。
It seems that way.
そのようですね。
A small battalion on a mission came
upon such a facility by accident.
任務中の小隊が　偶然に
正体不明の施設を発見した。
帰還した小隊の報告によれば→
According to their report
upon their return,
it seems to be a research facility
that was abandoned by Orochimaru.
どうやら　大蛇丸が遺棄していった
研究施設の一つらしい。
Did they go inside and investigate?
小隊は　中を調べたのですか？
Fortunately, not yet.
幸いにして　まだじゃ。
何があるか　わかりませんからね。
Right, since we don't know
what's inside.
わしは　あやつの
おぞましき研究の中身を→
I do not want members
of our village
to learn about his repulsive
research activities...
里の者に知られたくないのじゃ。
of what happened to
their missing kin and friends.
行方不明になった肉親や仲間が
どうなったのかをな。
However, an investigation is necessary.
だが　調査の必要はある。
そこで　俺にというわけですね。
So, you want me to go?
It's been three years since
Orochimaru left the village.
大蛇丸が里抜けしてから
３年も経つが→
But he still remains
a thorn in our side.
いまだに　あやつの負の遺産に
悩まされる。
I hate to ask you,
but please take care of this.
すまぬが頼むぞ。
はっ。
Yes, sir.
大蛇丸のアジトを見つけたそうだな。
I understand Orochimaru's hideout
was found.
It's one of his research facilities.
あやつの残した研究施設だ
すでに調査要員を派遣した。
I've dispatched someone
to investigate.
I see...
そうか。
何か気がかりでも？
Is something troubling you?
He could have set some kind
of trap before abandoning it.
捨ておかれた研究施設とはいえ
ヤツはトラップを残したかもしれん。
Are you sure it's safe
to investigate?
その調査役は　大丈夫かとな。
I sent an experienced and
qualified ANBU agent.
暗部の手だれを派遣した。
I hope nothing goes amiss.
何事もなければよいな。
SEAL
うっ！
Is that you, Kinoe?!
お前…　甲か。
It's been awhile, Kakashi.
お久しぶりですね　カカシさん。
What are you doing here?
どうして　ここに？
任務ですから。
I'm on a mission.
As my back-up?
俺のバックアップに？
No, that isn't it.
いや　違うな。
Did Lord Danzo dispatch
a Foundation shinobi,
ダンゾウ様か。
大蛇丸の研究施設を
自分たちでも調べようと→
because he's interested in
Orochimaru's research facility?
根を派遣した？
Foundation shinobi never discuss
their mission... Is that it?
根の者は任務を
何もしゃべらないか。
だが　何にせよ助かった。
No matter.
You did help me out there.
We can't have you burned
to a crisp.
カカシさんが燃えてしまっては
僕も困ります。
一緒に中を調査するか？
Do you want to investigate
what's inside together?
Whatever we find,
we'll share the intel with each other.
お互い何か発見したら
情報は伝え合うということで。
どうした？
What's wrong?
We may work in different divisions,
but we're Leaf shinobi.
部署は違っても同じ木ノ葉の忍だ。
Let's cooperate.
協力しても　いいんじゃないか？
Yes...
そうですね。
Who knows if a demon or
a snake will appear?
鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
わかりません。
Let's go together.
一緒に行きましょうか。
よし。
Right.
トラップは入り口のあれ
１つのようだな。
The only trap seems to have been
that one by the entrance.
大蛇丸も逃げるにあたって
時間はなかったはずだ。
Orochimaru was pressed
for time in his rush to escape.
You're right.
Still, we must be careful.
そうですね。　でも用心は必要です。
あぁ。
Yeah...
Let's go.
行くぞ。
はい。
Right.
There's nothing in here.
何もありませんね。
大蛇丸は　ここで
何の実験をしていたんだ？
What was Orochimaru
experimenting on in here?
お得意の人体実験の
たぐいだろうが…。
Probably doing what
he does best.
Experimenting on
human test subjects...
人体実験…。
Human test subjects...
((大蛇丸：これもダメ。
This one's no good.
This one as well.
あれも　それも。
That one too...
They're all no good...
どれもダメ。
This human experiment is a failure.
この人体実験は失敗ね。
成長期の子供のほうが→
I thought that an adolescent
would adjust far better
柱間細胞の増殖に
適応するかと思ったけど。
in propagating Hashirama's cells, but...
But it's just the opposite.
逆にダメね。
A child doesn't have the strength
or stamina to endure it.
子供じゃ体力もなく
耐えきれないわ。
I guess I'll have to
shut this place down.
ここは　もう
閉鎖するしかないわね。
《待って》
Wait!
But not to worry.
（大蛇丸）心配しなくていいわよ。
There are many more ways
of cell implantation.
細胞の移植には
他の方法も　いろいろあるわ。
I'll start the next test right away.
(すぐに次の実験を始めるから))
Wait, wait...
《待って　待って　待って！》
Wait!
甲…。
Ki... noe.
Hey, Kinoe.
おい　甲　行くぞ！
Let's go.
Right.
はい。
This one's locked.
ここは鍵が　かかっている。
Leave it to me.
任せてください。
It's open.
開きましたよ。
That jutsu went extinct in
the Hidden Leaf Village ages ago.
木ノ葉の里からたえて久しい
その術→
So how did you learn it?
お前　どうやって覚えたんだ？
It's a secret.
秘密です。
Are you aware that
the Wood Style jutsu
木遁術は木ノ葉にとって
重要な意味を持つ。
is extremely important to
the Hidden Leaf?
それを知っているか？
さぁ。
I didn't know that.
木ノ葉には九尾の人柱力がいる。
The Jinchuriki of the Nine Tails
belongs to the Hidden Leaf.
The Wood Style Jutsu is
one of the powers
木遁術は九尾をコントロールできる
力のひとつだ。
that can control the Nine Tails.
I know that the Sharingan
is the other power.
もうひとつが
写輪眼だということは→
知っています。
Your Wood Style Jutsu isn't just
for the Foundation...
お前の木遁術は根だけでなく→
It is a power meant to serve
all of Hidden Leaf Village.
もっと広く木ノ葉の里
全体のためになる力だ。
Lord Danzo wants to
keep you at his side.
ダンゾウ様は　お前を手もとに
置いておきたいのだろうが→
But you are more suited
to working directly under the Hokage.
本来なら火影直轄のほうが
ふさわしいはずだ。
Don't you want to leave
the Foundation
お前も根ではなく→
and come out of the shadows?
もっと日の当たる場所に
出たくないか？
No... no... I'm still alive!
《イヤだ　イヤだ。
まだ僕は生きてる！》
N-No...
《イヤだ…》
((ダンゾウ：生き残りか))
There's a survivor?!
What is this?
何だ　これは？
中に何かあるぞ。
There's something's inside.
何の真似だ　甲！？
What's going on, Kinoe?!
Kinoe!
甲！
お前　本気か！？
Are you serious?!
はい　本気です！
Yes, I'm serious!
《先手はとった　あとは…》
I have the advantage.
All that's left is...
《アイツ　写輪眼との
戦い方を知っている。
He knows how to fight
against my Sharingan.
最初から　やる気で…》
This was his intent
from the very beginning...
甲！　お前が本気で
俺を殺そうというのなら→
Kinoe!
If you're serious about killing me,
then I won't hold back!
俺も本気だ！
仲間同士で殺し合いだぞ！
It will be a death match,
friend against friend!
本気です。
I'm serious.
I'm dead serious!
本気で来たんです！
ううっ！
なぜ俺の命を狙う！？
Why do you want to kill me?
任務ですから。
It's my mission.
仲間の命を狙う任務などあるか！？
What kind of mission sends
a friend after a friend?!
変なこと言いますね。
You're one to talk.
仲間殺しの
カカシさんともあろう人が。
You're the one who killed a friend.
分身！？
A substitute?!
木遁分身…
あの頃より腕を上げたな。
Wood Style Substitute...
You've gotten better
since the last time...
Yes. So don't hold back, Kakashi.
ええ　だから
カカシさんも本気でどうぞ。
I won't kill a friend!
俺は仲間を殺さない！
遠慮ならいりません。
No need to hold back!
やめろ　甲！
この任務は放棄しろ！
Stop, Kinoe! Abandon this mission!
忍にとって任務は絶対です！
A shinobi's mission is absolute!
甲！
Kinoe!
任務は絶対じゃない！
A mission is not absolute!
仲間を殺せというのが任務ならば
その任務は間違いだ。
If your orders are to kill a friend...
that order is wrong!
The one who gave you
such an order is wrong.
お前に　そう命じたヤツが
間違っている！
Is Lord Danzo wrong?
《ダンゾウ様が間違っている？》
((歩けるか？
Can you walk?
What's the matter?
どうした？　己が誰かを
忘れているようだが→
You don't seem to remember
who you are...
言葉まで忘れたか？
but have you forgotten
how to talk as well?
あ…　いえ。
Uh, no...
ついてこい。
Follow me.
大蛇丸は欲張りすぎだ。
Orochimaru is greedy.
次々と新しいことを
試すのはよいが→
It's good to have the desire
to test out new things,
but he gives up too quickly.
見切りも早すぎる。
だが　お前は見切りを
つけられて幸いであったな。
However, you're lucky
he gave up on you.
If you had stayed
with Orochimaru,
大蛇丸のもとにおれば→
you would have ended up
another test subject.
更なる実験の材料に
されていたであろう。
My organization takes in shinobi
who have nowhere to go.
わしの組織は
行き場をなくした忍たちを→
引き取っている。
お前も　これより→
From now on, you will be
a shinobi of the Foundation.
根の忍となるがいい。
根？
The Foundation?
Yes. We are the tenacious Foundation.
そうだ　わしらは
この木ノ葉の里という→
We support the great tree known
as the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
大木を支える頑強な根だ。
根が十分に張らなければ
巨木は育たぬ。
Without strong roots,
a large tree cannot grow.
だから　根…。
That's why the Foundation...
お前は甲と名乗るがよい。
You will be called Kinoe.
お前も　これから
わしらの仲間だ。
Henceforth, you are one of us.
You were one of 60.
６０分の１だ。
え？
Huh?
木遁使いを生み出すために
他の５９人の子供が失われたのだ。
In order to produce a Wood Style user,
59 other children have been lost...
甲よ　その命　大事にしろよ。
Kinoe, cherish your life.
はい。
Yes.
行ってくるよ。　僕は
木ノ葉の根っこになるんだって。
I'm leaving.
He said I'm going to be one of
the Foundation of the Hidden Leaf.
Water Style!
水遁！
You're able to infuse chakra
quite nicely now.
チャクラをだいぶ
練られるようになったな。
Yes!
はい！
All right. I shall train you myself.
ようし！
そろそろ　わしが鍛えてやろう。
Lord Danzo is? Directly?
ダンゾウ様が！？
自ら！？
Personally?
直接？
わしはかつて
初代火影様の戦いを見た。
I once saw the First Hokage
in battle.
樹界降誕　花樹海降臨。
Deep Forest Emergence...
Deep Forest Bloom...
Such formidable
Wood Style Ninjutsu.
いずれも強力な木遁忍術であった。
その細胞を受けついだ
お前ならと思っている。
If you have inherited his cells,
I put all my hopes in you...
Manipulate the Earth Style
and Water Style
土遁　水遁の性質変化を
同時に扱うのだ。
Change in Chakra Nature
simultaneously!
まだ無理か。
すみません。
Not quite yet.
I'm sorry.
It can't be helped.
しかたあるまい。
You are not an exact copy
of the First Hokage.
お前は　初代様の完全なコピーでは
ないのだからなぁ。
これは　初代様が残した
木遁の忍術書だ。
Here is the Ninjutsu Scroll left
by the First Hokage.
わしには使えぬ術ばかりだが→
It's full of jutsu that I can't use,
but you should be able
to learn them.
お前ならば　習得できるであろう。
Me? Learn jutsu that you cannot,
Lord Danzo?
ダンゾウ様にできない術を僕が？
忍の世界には
いくつもの力がひしめいている。
The world of the shinobi is filled
with a myriad of jutsu.
You cannot compete
with just one power.
ゆえに一つの力では対抗できぬ。
複数の力を融合し→
We must master various jutsu
and use those powers
to unite the shinobi world.
その力をもって
忍世界の統一をはからねばならぬ。
(お前の木遁忍術に
期待しているぞ))
I have high hopes
for your Wood Style Jutsu.
ダンゾウ様は間違っていない！
Lord Danzo is not wrong!
任務を遂行する！
I will fulfill my mission!
Why you...!
この！
あっ！
To hell with your mission!
何が任務だ！
I'll say it again!
もう一度　言う！
仲間を殺す任務なんてない！
Killing a friend is not a mission!
Then why did you kill her?!
だったら
あなたは　なんで殺した？
What?!
なに！？
のはらリンを　なんで殺した！
Why did you kill Rin Nohara?!
Why did you kill her?
Why did you kill her?!
なんで殺した？
You killed her because
it was your mission!
任務だから殺したんだろう！
勝手に　リンの名を口にするな！
Don't speak about Rin!
俺は暗部の任務で
木ノ葉の抜け忍や→
As part of my ANBU missions,
I've had to deal with Rogue Ninja
and traitors of the Hidden Leaf.
裏切り者を処分してきた。
So I can't help it if
I'm called Friend-Killer Kakashi...
仲間殺しのカカシ。
そう呼ばれて当然だ。
だがな！
But...
Rin was...
俺は　リンを…。
Why you...!
このっ！
I didn't want to kill her!
殺したくなんかなかった！
I couldn't protect my friend.
俺は仲間を守れなかった。
だから　リンは死んだ。
That's why Rin died...
この千鳥で！
from this Chidori...
Couldn't protect her...?
守れなかった？
Couldn't protect her...
守れなかった…。
僕を　殺しますか？
Are you going to... kill me?
Are you a friend
of the Hidden Leaf?
お前は　木ノ葉の仲間か？
それとも裏切り者か？
Or are you a traitor?
I'm not a traitor.
裏切り者ではありません。
Then what are you?
では　なんだ？
I am... Kinoe of the Foundation.
僕は　根の甲。
Then Kinoe... renounce your duty
to the Foundation.
なら甲　根の任務を放棄しろ。
できません。
I cannot.
Then I'll take you into custody
and turn you over to Lord Hokage.
では　お前を拘束し
火影様に引き渡す。
好きに…　してください。
Do whatever... you please.
I already know
wakatten da yo
it doesn't belong to anyone else
hoka no dare demo nakute
I'll follow all the rainbows in the sky
kono sora ippai no niji wo kakete miseru yo
now matter how much time passes I can never reach it
itsumade tattemo todokanai yo
I keep repeating the same thing every day
ato nankai mo kurikaesu nichijou
I'm chasing a future I once dreamed of
oikaketeru no wa itsuka jibun de egaita mirai
and I was blaming it all on someone else
mata dareka no sei ni shiteta
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I can't go on like this
kono mama ja dame na koto
can I even believe in the "future self" I saw with my own eyes anymore?
kono me de midashita ashita no jibun wa mou shinjite ii n desu ka
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I have to go
ikanakucha ikenai koto
beyond the rainbow there's another future waiting for me
niji no mukou de matteru mou hitotsu no mirai he
The Foundation is a unique
organization that supports
the large tree known as the Leaf,
from deep underground.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Shinobi of the Foundation
have no names.
美空ひばりです。
No emotion. No past.
No future.
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
We only have our missions.
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"A Shinobi of the Leaf."
A mission for the Foundation
is absolute, Kinoe...
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の
豪華な歌手の皆さんによる→
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。
皆さん　どうぞ
よろしくお願いいたします。